Downloaded @ subs4free.club
Subtitles by explosiveskull
In ancient Russia,
people said,
do not walk around
the lake at night.
The mermaid is waiting there,
and as soon as you share
your feelings of love with
her, she will stun you
and she will tickle you,
dragging you to the bottom.
And if you try to
resist her charms,
you will not be forgiven.
She will separate you
from the one you love.
She will torture you until
your very last day on earth.
You can only save
yourself if you give her
your most precious thing.
But the drowned woman has
never released anyone.
Because they lost their
love, they perished.
And now, you will
meet the same fate.
Misha.
Stop this, please.
Don't say a word, I beg you.
Be silent.
You hear me?
Give him back, take me.
Anya!
Hurry!
I'm sorry.
She's here.
Hand, give me your hand!
Give me your hand!
Knees together, point
your toes, that's good.
Roma, tell
me about the house.
Is it roomy?
That's enough for today.
Try not to be late tomorrow.
When I was a kid,
it seemed kinda big.
It's been 20 years
since I was last there.
And it's for sale, anyway.
So, we'll fix it up.
Why, and do what with it?
What do you mean?
Live there.
- All right, that's it.
- Hey!
Come on now, try it, carefully.
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
- Okay, now let go.
- Let go, shh.
- No, no, Roma, it won't work!
Come on, listen.
Nothing works unless
you try it yourself.
Trust the water,
it'll guide you.
I don't want to trust it.
Trust me then.
Okay. Okay.
Hold on, hold on.
Swim away, dude.
Hey, Marina, listen.
I gotta borrow
your fiancé today.
Why is that?
I'm arranging a
little entertainment
to celebrate the untimely
demise of his bachelorhood.
Ah, you are aware
that such things
often lead to the cancellation
of the wedding, right?
Ah, don't you worry.
I'll bring your boy home safe.
I'll come back alone.
We do have qualifications soon.
You wimpin' out?
Not me, you're the
one in trouble.
You won't be able to swim.
I won't, huh?
Well, Kitaev, sounds
like a challenge.
I mean it.
Race me two laps.
Let's see who won't
reach the line.
You're gonna lose.
Enough talk, come
over and prove it.
Okay, I'll be right back.
Let go of the side.
Be proud of yourself.
I'll just, just trust it.
Trust the water.
Don't cry, you'll
get me next time.
Breathe, just breathe.
Look at me, everything's fine.
Just breathe.
Breathe.
What's for dinner?
Faucet broke again.
Fix it, please.
Are you still mad
about the pool?
It was fine.
I got there in time.
Roma, I can't swim.
You promised to be around.
I left you at the edge, right?
What happened?
So is she pissed at you?
Yeah, it looks like it.
Ah, whatever.
She just freaked out a bit.
She'll get over it.
I shoulda stayed.
Come on.
The hell's that mean?
We're already gone, so what?
We'll see the house, chill out
for a while, enjoy
some fresh air.
Take it easy.
I mean, it's normal to freak
out before the wedding.
You worry, so does he.
Where is he, by the way?
- Who?
- Roma, silly.
Probably
at the summer house.
What summer house?
Mm, the old one
your father gave us,
you know, as a wedding gift.
Wait, our father has shown up?
Olga, don't move.
I don't know.
He sent the deed, the keys,
told us to sell it off.
I would rather fix
it up, to be honest.
Strange.
What's strange?
We haven't seen
him for 20 years.
Wow, it's still a dump.
I thought he sold it ages ago.
What's wrong with him?
Your father, I mean.
Did you see the
lake around there?
Yeah.
It's where my mother drowned.
Father went nuts because
of it, but I was a kid.
I don't remember.
I see.
Olga and I were
at our grandparents'.
I haven't seen him since.
Damn, that sounds bad.
Have you tried talking to him?
- Who, my dad?
- Yeah.
Give me some light.
I don't even know him.
What can he tell me?
About your mom, maybe.
Kit, we have electricity
in this place?
Check for a fuse box.
A fuse box, he says.
Ilya?
Yeah, what you doing down here?
Put the light down.
Whoa!
There must have been a flood.
Need to clean the drain.
- Yo!
- Hey, hey!
- I think we're here, guys.
- Is this the place, man?
This place
looks haunted as shit.
- Come on, hurry up!
- What the hell is this, Ilya?
What do you think?
I told you we need to chill out.
Come on, it's fine.
- Yeah, yeah, come on in.
- I'm not in the mood.
I know you're not.
I'm fixing your mood.
We used to tell fortunes
with my mom for fun.
We'd look into two mirrors
opposite each other
and see if we can
spot Mr. Right.
Well, did you see him?
Course not,
it's nonsense.
What, burning your hair is not?
I don't believe in
the Mr. Right thing,
I do believe in
the power of hair,
and one shouldn't leave
it behind, even here.
Don't worry about Roma.
You're a great couple.
No need to fight, okay?
Okay, bye.
All right!
Hey, guys, to the groom.
Marina's a nice girl, of course.
No, really, I mean it, but
this is a life sentence.
Yeah.
So, buddy, to
spend the last days
of your bachelor
life to the fullest,
from us to you,
we got you a present.
Let's get this party started!
Yeah, yeah, bring 'em in!
Oh, ho, ho!
Guys, thank you.
No offense, okay,
you all have fun.
I gotta take a walk.
Ah, what?
He's acting weird.
- What happened?
- Come on, man.
Do you love me?
Roma!
- Roma!
- Kitaev!
Kit, Kit!
- Where you at?
- Roma!
Kit, where are you?
Kitaev!
Roma, where are you?
Rome, what are you
doing on the ground?
Roma, what are
you doing on the ground?
Guys, give me a hand.
- Where's the girl?
- What girl?
- All right, let's go.
- There was a girl here.
Where is she?
What friggin' girl?
Been there for long?
Long enough
to see these bloom.
Your arms, Kitaev, your arms!
Ulyanov, speed up,
longer oars, longer!
Rodionov, how many
times do I need to say,
keep your elbows underwater?
What's going on, huh?
Qualification's tomorrow.
Rome, don't piss
away our hard work.
Did something happen, Rome?
Feel sick, got a fever, what?
Didn't sleep well.
I'll be fine by tomorrow, coach.
Uh-huh, first position.
Keep swimming 'til
you get it right.
Coach Nikolayevich, Marina and I
were planning on
having dinner together.
You could do that.
Up to you.
Are you feeling all right?
I'm fine.
Doesn't look like it.
Everything's fine.
You sure?
Yeah, man.
Do you love me?
Marina, stop it.
I'm not feeling very well.
Enough already!
I'll sue your damn
coach into the ground.
He shouldn't have let you
swim when you're this sick.
Here, drink it.
Lie down.
Come on, lie down, lie down.
You're burning up.
I don't love you.
How is he feeling?
Looks better, I guess, asleep.
Good.
I was wondering, though,
why do you need to
fix the place up?
I mean, you can find
an agent and sell it.
Easier for everyone,
don't you think?
I don't know. I'd have to
discuss it with Roma first.
Had another fight?
No, no.
Just, um, he's acting strange.
Maybe he met someone.
No way.
I found something.
- Look.
- Looks like junk.
Hold it closer.
Did you ask where it came from?
Mm-mm.
See, you're
winding yourself up.
Go get some rest.
It'll be okay.
Thanks, Olga.
Bye.
See ya.
Rome?
Quiet, be quiet.
Just a dream,
it was just a bad dream.
Shh.
He's got a nice speed.
It's impressive.
This race is over.
Attention, please, Kitaev,
Rodionov, get ready.
Okay, guys, keep your speed.
Remember the technique.
Ilya, elbows.
Roma, like yesterday.
Now, go on, good luck.
- Pass me a water.
- Yeah, sure, which one?
Thank you.
Do you love me?
No, no, no.
Help, need
some help over here.
Hey, what happened?
What's wrong, is he all right?
Just breathe,
okay, just breathe.
We got you, come on.
Wake up. It's gonna be all
right, just hang on.
- Come on, all right?
- Breathe.
There was a young girl,
barely a teenager.
I can't shake the
feeling she's around.
Every time I close my
eyes, I see her face.
What face?
She's like a wild animal.
Roma, the doctor says
you got dehydrated.
You just need to sleep it off.
You're tired.
No, that's not the point.
Tell us more, Roma.
Where did you first see her?
On the lake.
She was wearing my shirt.
I was drawn to her.
He's delirious.
There was nobody there.
I swear I couldn't help myself.
We kissed, and I felt
like I couldn't breathe.
- Rome.
- Marina, I'm sorry.
I just couldn't help myself.
Please, Marina!
Roma, listen to me.
What else do you remember?
- What did she look like?
- Okay, hold on.
Roma, come back!
Marina.
Marina, Marina!
He doesn't need you.
Marina?
Marina.
Roma, what's wrong?
Rome!
Somebody, please,
we need some help!
Hurry!
Roma!
Kit, Kit, open up!
He doesn't look good.
He's on death's door.
Should we take him back?
We have to go and meet
with someone first.
Hello, Dad.
You gave Roma the house.
Why?
You shouldn't
have come here.
I'm sick.
Roma saw the girl on the lake.
With the long hair.
She took his shirt,
and now he's ill.
That's impossible.
She died a long time ago.
Do you recognize this?
No, I don't.
Now, leave.
Father, what exactly
happened 20 years ago?
- Olga.
- Speak up now!
- Olga!
- How did Mom die?
- Olga, that's enough!
- Your son may be next.
Leave me be!
I'm begging you, please!
- Tell us!
- Stop it, get out!
You can't
hide your whole life.
She drowned, all right!
She drowned!
Dad.
You... don't talk to her.
- Don't you dare talk to her!
- Who?
She'll take you away!
Don't you, don't
you dare!
I met her on the lake.
She asked if I loved her.
I didn't answer,
so she kept coming back,
torturing me the entire time.
I couldn't escape from her.
Your mother, she somehow
found a way to get rid of her.
I called her by her name,
but it didn't work,
and she took your mother away.
She never came back.
From that day, everything lost
its meaning, everything but her.
I think about her
every single day.
Not your mom, but her.
I see her hair, her eyes.
I can never forget her.
What did Mom
do specifically?
Not sure.
Under the old dock, she found
something under the water.
Except it won't
help you, my son.
She will drive you mad.
Let's go
to this damn lake.
We need to know what
your mother did.
Sit, sit, sit.
Everything okay?
It's been 20 years,
but nothing here has changed.
Marina, you're not
mad at Kitaev, are you?
He was out of his mind,
you know.
None of your business,
get in the water.
Everything'll be fine.
Stay with Roma, please.
Hey, swimmer boy, come with me.
So, what, are you in charge now?
Come on, we can't
do it without you.
Don't be scared.
Please forgive me.
We can deal with this.
We'll sort it out together.
Let me
get you some water.
Right here's where I found
him, with the comb next to him.
Mm-hmm.
Take your clothes off.
You need to dive in.
Shit.
Got it!
Ilya!
Lisa.
Lisa Grigorieva's
her name.
Take what's yours.
Give me the loved one.
Take.
Take what's yours.
Give me the loved one.
Give me the loved one!
Roma!
Rome.
Roma.
I saw her.
Who?
Your mother.
Rome!
Roma!
Drink this.
You'll feel better.
Maybe it's all about the comb.
LG, Lisa Grigorieva.
Lisa.
Suicide.
What makes you think
she committed suicide?
Suicide victims weren't
buried in cemeteries.
So, what, they buried
her in the lake?
On the shore.
The lake spilled over
when the dam was built.
Well, what should we do?
This has to be it.
We shouldn't have
taken her comb.
"Take what's yours and
give me the loved one."
You were saying that
power's in the hair.
Could the comb be it?
Your mom was performing
a ritual in the bath.
What do you think?
Ritual?
Well, it didn't work
for her, not an option.
What else is there?
I say we get out of here.
No, she'll find him anywhere.
We need to fight.
What is it, Rome?
Rome, what happened?
Are you cold?
Can I get you a blanket?
Marina.
There's nobody under there.
We have to do something.
I'm trying the ritual.
Do me a favor and stay here.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Scream if something goes wrong.
I'm here.
Lisa Grigorieva.
Take what's yours.
Give me the loved one.
When I was a kid,
I had a dream.
I'm in the house, alone.
Parents are out.
And then suddenly, I
hear someone outside.
He says, "Open the door,"
but I don't open it.
And the door slowly
opens, all by itself.
Hinges creak.
The deadbolt turns.
Somehow, I'm on my
way to open the door.
Mom is standing there.
She looks at me and whispers,
"I'm taking the one who's
home alone, the one you love"
And I'm scared.
Do you love me?
I do.
Did you hear that?
Roma?
Roma.
What are you doing?
Take me.
Roma.
I can't
bear this anymore.
Take me.
Roma!
What are you doing?
- Enough.
- I can't bear it.
- That's enough!
- I can't do this anymore.
Lisa Grigorieva,
take what's yours
and give me the loved one.
We used to tell
fortunes with my mom for fun.
We'd look into two mirrors
opposite each other
and see if we can
spot Mr. Right.
Lisa Grigorieva,
take what's yours
and give me the loved one.
Do you love me?
More than life itself.
Look who's here.
No, no, go.
You said you loved
me more than life itself.
Go away.
He doesn't love you.
Go away, go away,
go away, go away!
Murderer!
Quiet, shh.
Quiet.
Marina.
Marina, Marina.
Do you love me?
And me?
How 'bout me?
Do you love me?
- And me?
Choose me.
I love you.
I think it worked.
She took the comb.
Not going to rain today.
- How are you?
- I'm fine.
Get in, we're leaving.
Ready?
Your mother was beautiful.
Let's get out of here.
I do love you.
Where is Ilya?
He followed you.
Here.
Get in, I'll be right back.
Yo!
Ilya.
I'll take
everyone you love.
Roma!
Roma, hold on!
Hold on to me!
Let's go!
Where's Ilya?
She got to him.
What the?
Come on.
Son of a...
- Roma!
- Wait a sec.
Rome, Roma, Roma!
Roma, she's here!
Roma!
Rome!
What?
We gave the comb back.
- We gave the comb back.
- We were wrong.
It's not about the comb.
She needs something else.
She needs me.
No... Rome!
Don't do it!
Stop!
Rome, Roma!
Rome!
Do you love me?
I do.
No!
You love her!
Lisa Grigorieva, take the bride.
Give my brother back.
Olga.
Lisa Grigorieva, take the bride.
Give my brother back.
What's wrong with you?
She can't be killed, see?
She can't.
It's a life for a life.
Mom gave hers for Dad,
so you give yours for Roma.
Sorry.
Olga, Olga, please,
untie me.
- Olga, Olga.
- Lisa Grigorieva.
- Take the bride.
- Please, I'm begging you.
Give my brother back.
Olga, Olga, please, untie me.
I'm begging you, don't do this!
Lisa Grigorieva,
take the bride!
Give my brother back.
Let me out of here!
You have to!
Lisa Grigorieva, take the bride.
Olga!
This will not work.
Your mother
volunteered her life.
It can't be forced.
Get the hell back!
We can only feed
her with our love.
And then she turns
it into hatred.
Agony.
She wants us to suffer.
I was weak.
You are strong.
You're stronger than
any of us, dear.
You have your mother's
eyes, same eyes.
I won't leave Roma.
I won't leave him.
You don't have to.
We'll find a way out, dear.
Forgive me.
Dad.
Dad!
I haven't seen you for so long.
Take me.
Leave them alone.
No, Dad.
I still love you.
Dad!
Dad, Dad, please!
Rome, Roma!
We were wrong.
It's not about the comb.
Rome, her power is in her hair.
You need to cut it off,
do you hear me?
Just cut off her hair!
Rome, Rome!
Rome, Rome, Rome!
A life for a life.
Mom gave hers for Dad.
Give him back.
Take me.
Do you love me?
Of course.
Hey!
Wake up.
Wake up!
No!
Please, I made it!
Please, I made it in time!
Wake up!
Breathe!
Subtitles by explosiveskull